hey everyone so this is a reupload of
the London real update with coffee Zilla
which was put up a while ago and was
just taken down because of a copyright
claim from London real for that back
story watch the film that's going out at
the same time as this it's a short
update and explains how London really
using copyright law pretty cynically to
avoid scrutiny but I've taken out all of
the copyright material from this so that
it doesn't get flagged again so that it
will go up and will give a lot of the
back story we've also put the original
investigation on our website via bit
shoot so if you want to see that go to
the website so I hope this is gonna be
the last film about the London real
situation I'd much prefer be making
films about the wider issues raised by
it kind of free speech censorship but it
is such a good story and I feel that
it's worth rounding it off and I thought
the best way to do that would be to have
a dialogue with coffee Zilla so coffee
Zilla is an American youtuber who's also
been following the story so I'm gonna
play the whole conversation and in it we
talked about the recent meltdown on
YouTube and how the London real army
seems to be turning against Brian Rose I
can't imagine a bigger trainwreck with
your audience because basically he was
getting all these questions all this
pressure and it's like one day he just
snapped he's cursing at his audience
calling them fools it was insane it was
absolutely insane I've never seen a
meltdown quite like this and I was just
waiting for it to be deleted and it was
up for at least 24 hours and just to be
clear it was deleted eventually yeah and
also the central question of whether the
entire fundraising scheme makes any
sense at all it's the it's the funniest
thing in the world to me because it
makes zero sense
as soon as Brian rose said that I was
like okay your whole thing makes zero
since you've raised all this money for
nothing other than yourself and your own
ego about having your own platform so
we're gonna record an update to the
London real investigation London real
situation I'm joined by coffee Zilla
who's been doing his own follow ups on
the London real situation Thank You
travelling coffee Zilla Steven Steven
I'll say Steven from now on
and so I think both of us we've talked a
little bit offline before recording this
and I think both of us feel a little bit
torn like we don't want to keep
returning to this story but it's also
such a great story I'd spend a bit of
time just kind of unpacking some of the
the wider issues what we've we've both
been contacted by other people who've
got knowledge of the situation and
there's lots of stuff that's been going
on I think it's worth unpacking and
revealing to people and also just some
of the it's it's an absolutely
compelling story just to see it
unfolding in real time just before we
kind of get into the details of it where
are you at with it at the moment I'm
where you are I'm sort of tired of this
piece but also I can't stop looking it's
almost like a horrible car crash or
something like that
full disclosure I've what I was watching
landed real before this whole thing
happened and I saw his content it was
going in a certain direction and I feel
like I felt and a lot of people felt
that recently he has completely shifted
into a new direction and there are a lot
of questions about you know this
fundraising he's been doing how
transparent he's been and yeah I feel
like at this point I'm so far in that I
I have to at least wrap the bow tie the
bow whatever before letting this thing
go finally yeah I feel similarly
I've been trying I mean I was primarily
interested in it for the wider issues
that it put put out there free speech
censorship but the weaponization of free
speech is just a huge in huge thing as
well like playing the censorship cloud
playing the free speech card and for me
I feel that those are such powerful
cards and such important cards that
we've got to be kind of very aware and
very careful about kind of how that's
used and how that can be abused and I
think just to bring people up to date
there has been something of a backlash
which we'll get to soon like the
audience his own audience people who've
donated money especially have kind of
been asking some pretty tough questions
and also there's another angle that
you're much more familiar with than I am
which is other sort of business
practices he's brought in this five
coins to five million with with tikka
tikka khari tikka Tiwari tickety
to worry tiga Tiwari and another another
business guy and you've you've actually
focused really carefully on that in a
lot of the other films that you've put
out yeah I think it's like a it's it's a
massive question a massive problem when
you have someone you know raising
raising all these funds for in the name
of freedom but also collecting all these
emails also getting all this attention
and saying like I'm the guy that you
guys can trust to give you the truth but
then you're selling some crypto what I
characterize as a scam and that becomes
all of a sudden a problem I I think what
you said is true
weaponizing freedom of speech because
it's such a powerful motivator it's of
course a universal human value so when
you hear hey I'm the freedom of speech
guy who's gonna say no to that
right like everybody's a freedom of
speech guy almost so so I think it's
important to say that look I don't agree
with YouTube's
you know censorship here I said that
from day one of even about David Icke
day one I said you know what I don't
believe with them just taking him down I
think there needs to be a broader
discussion but what's happened is he's
weaponized that and turned it into let
me fundraise 4 million dollars because
I'm the guy that's gonna protect free
speech and that's just simply not the
truth I think this is a sacred value and
it really yeah I feel I feel very
energized by when when that is is
weaponized and then it gets caught up in
like we're in we're in a struggle with
the tech platforms a lot of us feel like
we're in a struggle with the tech
platforms we're worried about being
demonetized were worrying about worrying
about we're worried about having some of
our stuff taken down so I think we've
got a basically clean house we've got to
kind of call out the people who are
using those really powerful arguments
for their own benefits
yeah for sure I think the question here
is what's the intention behind the
digital freedom platform I think that's
a large question I mean whether he's
spending the money poorly or not
what are Brian roses intentions because
for a long time he's been saying oh I
just care about free speech I just care
about this I'm being silenced bubbeleh
one thing I brought sort of to light
though in one of my recent videos is
that Brian Rose's channel has never been
doing better he has seized an
opportunity
and his views went like this he was like
kind of stagnant and then all of a
sudden he starts talking about
censorship he's like this in terms of
use in terms of subscribers in terms of
people backing him in terms of donations
in terms of people for his email list in
terms of his own audience pool within
his audience that was already there all
of a sudden they care a lot more and so
you have to wonder with each thing he's
doing is he doing it because he wants
freedom of speech or is he capitalizing
on what could be characterized as an
extremely lucrative situation yeah and
let's recap I mentioned a few things in
that little spiel before one of which
was the the fact that he supposedly
raised a million it's hard to know
because the the counter was actually on
the London real site I was skeptical
that he actually had but you you think
that he may well have done which I think
is worth unpacking in itself but also
what happened next cuz then there was
this stage six or phase six money-making
thing which was we need two hundred and
fifty thousand a month to keep this
thing running yeah I think it's worth
going back a little bit because it's all
happened so that now if you weren't
present for each subsequent stage you
could think oh it was always planned out
to be for six phases and this is one of
my biggest criticisms of London real so
it started with phase one oh I'm gonna
livestream a million people then right
after he reaches his goal all of a
sudden he introduces phase two and three
he didn't even have four or five and
four five and six yet that's all came on
later so then he goes okay all I'm
raising for is now more controversial
voices and blockchain where he got
blockchain from nobody knows cuz nobody
really understands why it's necessary
it's not so then he raises that money
then he goes okay well now I need to
raise more money and the the logic there
was that okay David give me money
because really the intention is just to
fundraise to the end of our fundraising
date and then I'm shutting it off the
only you know rationale for putting more
and more stretch goals was always well
we're just gonna continue fundraising
continue taking your money until we go
to the fundraising date that was always
the plan that was the whole rationale
for creating nine hundred thousand
dollars in stretch goals and then all of
a sudden the fundraising ends he raised
his over million dollars I believe he
did I believe he did and I'll explain
that in a second but
then he all of a sudden moves on without
missing a beat without any kind of
explanation
it's okay well now we need running costs
and he hikes up the price to another
three million dollars over the calendar
year but why I think he actually raised
the money because it doesn't make sense
for him to put I think the donation
fatigue that it creates in your audience
when you if you lied about raising a
million dollars is not worth the press
of raising a million dollars like who
wants to rate who wants to donate to a
guy who's already has a million dollars
like nobody so I think of anything if
you were to lie about a donation you
would probably under under represent it
but I just generally think I don't know
one way or the other I think it just if
we just think in terms of rational
actors he probably didn't lie about it
yeah I mean I think it's worth digging
into that because my sense was that the
that he probably didn't raise a million
I mean that the count was on his website
it was hard to verify there was no
verification but you've looked at these
kind of tactics before and you feel you
think that people have raised that kind
of money doing this kind of thing before
is that would that be a fair summary oh
yeah if the skepticism is a million
dollars is a lot of money fear not
because the the tactics that's he's
employing here or what I see all the
time among fake gurus and it's the
persuasion tactics that I see all the
time among internet marketers and in
London real actually has been leveling
up I mean he's been improving his game
quite considerably because for a while
you know he didn't name his his audience
all of a sudden with this thing came
along he goes oh you guys are the line
of real army right now
that's brilliant it tribe Eliza's your
audience and all of a sudden there's a
bad guy because what does an army do it
fights I jokingly call my my followers
the coffee's little army as like a play
on what all these gurus do but like
seriously it's a great way to try belies
your audience and go oh we're standing
for something we're a team we're
together right so he gets his audience
together and then who's the enemy well
you have to get him an enemy oh it's the
big tech platforms who censored me and
we're going to war with the big tech and
it's a bit of a David Goliath story
let's be real which is also super
powerful persuasion tactic everyone
believes in the underdog right
everyone will fundraise for the underdog
so then it's poor poor Brian censored
Brian
he just needs your help and he's gonna
go to war and we're gonna be the brave
underdogs who are gonna win the day and
win free speech back it's this whole
message that's so powerful easily commit
can raise a million dollars and in fact
I think it's very evident the fact that
he's putting stretch goals beyond that I
think he believes and I think he's
probably right
if his audience doesn't turn against him
as it kind of is that he could have
raised more
yeah let's come to that because that
that was the most astonishing thing I
mean we both saw it on Sunday night so
he initially posted the a community post
on YouTube saying with a link to the
kind of statement come and sign up and
declare and that got really really bad
comments a lot of really negative
comments I I took a screenshot before he
do it he deleted that post and then a
couple of days later and then he posted
another one basically basically
criticizing his audience saying losers
focus on winners winners focus on
winning what have you been doing and
that got an even more kind of negative
response from people who've been who'd
actually given him money and then Brian
Rose himself was in the comments arguing
with his own audience basically and will
show some of this basically saying you
didn't donate I guess you didn't donate
I mean you've got some of those comments
in front to you what was what was your
favorite oh my gosh I mean there's it
may be worth reading off a few because
they're beautiful I like I can't imagine
a bigger trainwreck with your audience
because basically he was getting all
these questions all this pressure and
it's like one day he just snapped the
weird thing was the whole post was about
explaining the London real platform in
like a really passive-aggressive way but
then in the comment section any follow
up was met with I don't have to explain
myself so it's like this weird thing of
I'm explaining myself but I don't have
to explain myself because you're a loser
if you're questioning me and like the
way he went off to his audience was
insane
winners focus on winning see above
scammers this guy says scammers focus on
scamming and London real goes like you
let me guess you didn't donate here's
another one number one ask for money
linden real money gets shit done full
let me guess you're broke so let's
unpack that he's cursing at his audience
calling them fools that that may have
donated may have donated we don't know
in this case and then he goes let me
guess you're broke so he's belittling
his audience he's calling them dumb and
then it was it's a it was absolutely
insane I've never seen a meltdown quite
like this and I was just waiting for it
to be deleted and it was up for at least
24 hours
this guy says David Icke and Brian Rose
are controlled opposition sorry if you
don't see it London real you are a
controlled idiot sorry if you don't see
it and just to be clear it was deleted
eventually yeah and I was genuinely
concerned I I was kind of like wow this
is this is kind of extreme and then
yesterday he brought out another very
sort of slickly produced piece that was
clearly in response to that but he
obviously didn't mention it he didn't
mention that he'd done anything he
didn't mention any of the argument just
just sort of I need to be more
transparent clearly I have a problem
with communicating and I need to do
better
I got an unsettled feeling watching that
extremely unsettled because the
difference between what he said a day
ago and what he said the very next day
was so far apart it seemed like I was
watching I don't know what I'd say like
a chameleon something changing colours
purely based on environmental factors
which made it totally unbelievable you
know because one second he's calling his
audience idiots and then the next second
he's sitting in front of a camera saying
you know what I was bad at communicating
I want to explain this whole thing to
you guys I want to be open to criticism
it's like wait this is not the same
person we saw just yesterday and he
didn't address it at all either like he
deleted it
he won't address it he won't address the
fact that he was belittling his audience
whatever
so I think it's extremely strange and
like I think Brian just felt trapped and
I think it shows how much he can sort of
put it on you know like one second he
totally believes he doesn't need to
explain himself the next second I really
care about you guys and I really want to
do better and edit it out very weird
yeah and I think it's worth kind of
flagging up some of the other stuff that
we there's kind of happening in the
background as well I mean I've been sent
so we know that they delete some
comments off the YouTube channel they
also have their own internal London real
messaging system that is pre flagging
certain certain work keywords and
certain topics that you can't post so
that includes like someone someone sent
me some screenshots that that includes
dailymotion that includes snake-oil so
anyone trying to discuss the stuff
internally is not allowed to so I think
this is worth flagging up which is
another thing about sort of yes free
speech we can talk about anything but
don't question me I mean that's that's
really quite astonishing and then
another thing that we found out from
quite a few different places is that
there was a big a lot of his staff were
not happy about him doing the the David
Icke interview they thought it was not
the right into me to do in the current
situation they didn't want they didn't
think it was responsible they knew what
David Icke was gonna be saying when he
came on so a lot of his staff objected
to the David I continue don't happen
again at all and subsequent to lap 2
that a lot of them were either sacked or
made redundant quite quite a large
number of London real staff he went he
went from sort of what 14 or 15 staff
down to a very very small number of
staff that was before any of this
fundraising happened I think something
worth highlighting here is that we've
had people coming to us from behind the
scenes we haven't talked about this in
either of our investigations but with
some knowledge of the London real
situation we've got a much clearer
picture of what's going on that do raise
inconsistencies maybe help
because why you can make the free speech
argument like you said about David Icke
I don't even think you have to I think
you can simply point out the fact that
Brian Rose wants it both ways he wants
to on the one hand say he's all about
free speech free speech free speech you
can say whatever you want I fight for
free speech but on the other hand he
also wants to censor comments at a
critical of him like how can he want
YouTube to not censor anything of his
but he wants to censor his audience
himself he wants a control goes on his
on his digital freedom platform in his
own Terms of Service on the platform
that he says is so much for free speech
it says that long-stem limited at any
point can just remove anything they find
objectionable if that isn't a community
guidelines i've never heard of one
before like that it's just community
guidelines repurposed for Brian Rose it
it seems like this Brian Rose is unhappy
with YouTube calling the shots and so he
wanted to make a platform where he
called the shots but that doesn't get a
lot of press who's gonna build Brian
Rose his own platform well if all of a
sudden you call it the digital freedom
platform you get a lot more traction and
to speak about this as this skeleton
crew of employees for a second I think
it's worth talking about only in the
context of look Brian Rose wants to use
your fundraising and I'm talking to the
audience here the people who you know
donated to Brian rose he wants to use
that to hire more staff look look at his
phase 6 it's higher 20 people for
digital blah blah blah blah blah he just
fired people like that hasn't been
brought brought to light at all after
right after firing people
he's fundraising to hire people so he's
just moving people off his payroll and
moving it right on to the audiences
payroll and I think people should be
upset about I think they have the right
to be upset about it because things
aren't being transparently communicated
here yeah I wanted to also just ask
because something you said yesterday
when we when we chatted before this made
a lot of sense and I don't think it's
been spelled out and that is just a
major kind of issue with the whole thing
because also in his in his latest
message he said yes I used dailymotion
which was a part of the the initial film
that I put out like actually he's using
dailymotion it's not a
not a private streaming but you you
actually kind of flagged up that there's
no real reason given that he's already
said look I'll use free platforms and
save your money if like if I can because
I'm caring about how I'm spending your
money there's no real reason to him to
be doing any of this because you should
be using bit sheet it's the it's the
funniest thing in the world to me
because it makes zero sense
as soon as Brian Rose said that I was
like okay your whole thing makes zero
since you've raised all this money for
nothing other than yourself and your own
ego about having your own platform
because listen guys listen to me for a
second okay think about it this way what
costs all the money
live streaming why not just do like put
it on bit shoot right they're not going
to censor you this thing already exists
you don't have to pay for it your your
supporters sure don't have to pay for it
embed it in your platform and then all
of a sudden say this guy's we're not
gonna do it live what's so hard about
that why does he need to do it live it's
not like he's he's a twitch streamer who
reads off donations it's not like he
interacts with the audience
give me one rationale for why
live-streaming is so critical when it's
the most expensive part and he says in
his little thing right
I'm extremely frugal I would never spend
your money if I don't have to but all of
a sudden there's this ego trip about it
has to go up live why the majority of
people who watch content are watching it
pre-recorded like that's just how it
works it's fine and also you can pre
record and do a premiere like people do
on YouTube kind of simulate the liveness
of it I mean I always rag on people for
doing pre-recorded webinars and
pretending it's live but this would be
the one instance where I would I would
give Brian Rose full permission and I
wouldn't rag on him for doing a
pre-recorded live webinar if it was to
save people millions of dollars in
pointless live streaming costs that
ultimately again what does it serve
except for Brian Rose's ego to think
about two two possibilities one he
builds his digital freedom platform for
millions of dollars and you get a live
stream the other is he just embeds it on
bit shoot where costs $0 tell me the
difference in actual like practice if
you if I don't think Brian Rose can do
it it makes zero sense it's gets me
fired up because this is the whole thing
this is the entire thing is he keeps
saying
I'm frugal I'm doing it for you guys got
it out we don't have a digital freedom
platform the most egotistical thing I
ever heard was we're creating the first
ever ever digital freedom platform it's
not in accepted name only like people
like bitch should have been doing this
forever there's a bunch of other
platforms as well who are freedom of
speech like platforms this is just
Brian's own spin-off and his own
egotistical you know ramblings about
yeah this is the first one ever
absolutely not
yeah and this is this is a slight segue
but it's why so you go back to a lot of
the platform wars patreon for example
there was a whole thing I think around
Christmas last year or the year before
where patreon kicked off sargon of akkad
and sam harris left Jordan Pederson left
we left rebel wisdom left we we now only
have a sign up on our website because
we're like we don't want to be at the
mercy of these big tech platforms just
making decisions on who who gets to be
who's who's a person and who's a nun
person and so a lot of us dealt with
these issues back then we thought about
these questions and obviously Jordan
peed and went Peterson went off and
created think spot the platform because
if you go and create a platform you have
to wrestle with actual issues like if
Brian Rose had gone off and said look we
need to create a digital freedom
platform and now are now aligned with
other people who wanted to do this
because we're all worried about this
issue that would have been a completely
different dynamic because in that but in
that dynamic he would have actually had
to face some of the problems that
everyone else has had to face when they
when they deal with this which is one do
you allow Nazis on your platform like
are you gonna have any gatekeeping
whatsoever who's gonna make those
decisions like we all you deal with
those questions if you actually deal
with the problem properly but he didn't
deal with the problem properly he just
basically said okay I'll create this
thing called a digital freedom platform
that's going to be independent of London
real even though it's not it's fully
owned by him and it's embedded within
the London real website can you talk
about that for a second because I think
that's like the weirdest thing that he
calls it a dependent when it's not um I
think it's worth just playing the clip
just
sort of back up that he did definitely
declare that was going to be the case
that's the thing that I can't get my
head around is why he ever said that if
it was always going to be hosted within
the London real website and I think you
mentioned something that because you you
called the cast to find out how much the
the stream was going to be or the stream
had been for the IKE interview and they
said so you've got a figure for that and
you also he kind of conceded that you
also worked out with that that was a
tacit admission what wouldn't you
explain that
sure yeah I'd love to first of all let
me take a big w on this because everyone
in my comment section was saying that I
was wrong about how much it cost and
like I was incorrect because of like
some technicality about what they said I
said it was 60 mm the real cost was 61
thousand or I might have that flip so I
was dead on okay let me let me hold that
real quick okay I'm done but the second
thing was about concerning the the rest
of the money right because he goes oh no
it really did cost $100,000 well why if
it only costs $60,000 to live shrimp
let's just recap I think you've said a
lot that maybe people weren't aware they
might not be following oh sure basically
he claimed it was gonna be a hundred
thousand dollars to stream like three
yes it was found out a few people found
out that it was done through day cast
knew called they cast and they said oh
hang on you said I want to stream to a
million people how much would that cost
and they said oh actually we've just
done that this weekend and it cost sixty
one thousand dollars that's correct yeah
and so Brian Rose later concedes that
point in in his little update or
whatever but then he quickly follows it
up with hey whoa wait but we had to
upgrade the servers on London real in
order to handle the the number of people
on the platform so not only do you have
to have live streaming bandwidth but you
also have to have server bandwidth for
your actual website itself but hang on
because that's upgrading London real
supposedly should be independent from
the digital freedom platform so again
the digital freedom platform is a
completely separate entity so he spent
sixty thousand dollars on the digital
freedom platform forty thousand dollars
upgrading his personal servers for line
and reel so it's not at all you're just
using money that your donators gave you
that you said wouldn't be used for
London real to upgrade London real
because that's where the digital freedom
platform is and now he's he's spending
some new thing about oh no I had to do
that because there's in such a short
timeframe now moving over but this is
one of a one of many things where he's
trying to like after the fact spin up
new narratives spin up some new
explanation the whole problem is that
the things he's saying turn out to be
lies him saying that he's gonna stop
fundraising he can maybe create a
rational afterwards but it turned out to
be a lie him saying that it's an
independent thing that he's not gonna
spend money from digital freedom
platform on lended real that is a lie he
admitted it in a video anyone can watch
right now
that he spent at least forty thousand
dollars or more on server space and
upgrades and whatever for London real it
doesn't make sense yeah and I wanted to
ask about the the other kind of business
practices because obviously he as you
conceived from the the socialblade stats
there's been a lot of visitors to London
real everyone who signed up to the
freedom platform was given their email
address and the very first emails that
people were sent were for what looks to
me like kind of get rich quick schemes
with so tikka Tiwari I if you actually
check him out he's he is no longer
licensed as a broker he was I don't want
to get I don't wanna get this wrong to
be very precise with the wording but you
I know that you like coffee Ziller what
you what you look at a lot is these kind
of get-rich-quick schemes the people
behind them and what's going on so I
love your take on on on all of that sure
thing
so yeah to give a little backstory tikka
Tiwari is this crypto guru
for a small fee of a few thousand
dollars I believe in this case it was
two thousand dollars you can get his
special newsletter where he's going to
break down the five coins to five
million dollars so five crypto coins and
you can make five million dollars if
that's not a get-rich-quick scheme I
defy you to find one but London real
what he did is he gets all these new
followers to his newsletter and then or
his email list and he does what is known
as renting out your list so it's
basically where you have this new and a
lot of people do this and I have a lot
of ethical problems with it but you have
some product you're pushing so you say
hey Steven I want to rent out your list
so you sell it for me and so I agree you
pay me some sum of money and maybe some
back-end kickbacks for if people buy
your product and I go and promote you on
my email list now the problem is is if
what you're selling is a scam then I'm
promoting a scam to my followers and I'm
making money off of the scam and so this
guy's out here he's charging thousands
of dollars for information that a lot of
people think can be found online for
free he's charging thousands of dollars
for a newsletter that's run by Agora one
of the largest newsletter manufacturers
and they're constantly pumping out
get-rich-quick schemes I could show you
probably I've like probably a hundred
letters from them saying this is the new
way to make a million dollars this is
this is the undiscovered thing and it's
their whole business model every month
every week every day they have some new
get-rich-quick scheme they get the
suckers to fall into it because who buys
into get-rich-quick schemes well it's
desperate poor people unfortunately I
wish that wasn't the case or old people
you know and and so this is what's
happening so Brian rose under the guise
of you know I have all these new emails
then sells a crypto scam well after he
sells it interestingly he deletes the
videos he deletes the evidence of him
promoting that scheme because now he's
made his money and he can move on
because the event had already happened
but then let's just stop let's just stop
that because sir I did see I didn't
notice that they have been deleted until
you pointed it out but so he sent he
sent the email out to his supporters
then had like two or three videos on
London real it was like four or five it
was like four or five is a lot with with
tika Tiwari pushing this this game and
then afterwards deleted those videos
which in itself is kind of bizarre thing
to do I mean he probably claimed that
YouTube took them down maybe but that
wouldn't make any sense because you know
there's a bunch of other tika to worry
videos up so they're not taking down
ticket to worry videos no Brian took
them down
I feel confident saying that and it's
because he got a backlash on it he'll
talk about like freedom and not give
transparency ride up to the point when
he's criticized and then he will change
tact right he go he promotes this crypto
thing right before he's criticized then
all of a sudden delete some videos he
says oh you guys are losers are sorry
your it he says you guys are idiots you
know you you can't question me I don't
have to explain this to you right up in
to the point where he gets criticized
then he turns around and says no no
actually I'm ready to be transparent
with you guys I'm ready to tell you the
truth and to be clear he's not done
promoting these types of things because
now he's promoting Tim Sykes you know a
somewhat infamous penny stocks trader
who has some really expensive courses
newsletters etc as well yeah it's I'm
also interested to hear a bit more about
some of these tactics because they seem
very like there's real similarities
between that and sort of quite kind of
culty dynamics like creating in groups
out groups not accepting criticism like
all of these things we actually put out
a film with Jamie wheel where he talked
about I think we called it how to how to
spot a cult and he said well obviously
you've got kind of cult II cults which
are kind of spiritually oriented but you
also get kind of lots of sales tactics
lots of sales techniques a kind of in
that same ballpark and we'll play with
those same same techniques the silencing
of criticism is huge
I cannot first of all i've been legally
threatened to you know stop talking
about what i'm talking about because
they don't like criticism i've had
students who get sued by the people they
take their course because then they
speak out and the per
doesn't like what they're saying so they
sue them you know there's a lot of ways
of engineering social proof and
engineering the lack of criticism which
is really common among these things you
have to build this unquestioning
following which is very hard to do on
the internet but can be done with the
right amount of money for legal to
basically force people to shut up with
the right amount of engineering SEO to
make sure your favorable favorable
results go to the top right so this is
super common which is definitely a cult
aspect was there anything that we missed
out that we were looking to cover I
think I think I have something that's
not right so David I want to ask you a
question which is you know London real
is in this very precarious situation
with his audience on the one hand he
wants to tell he wants to be transparent
enough to where he avoids the criticism
that he's not being transparent on the
other hand there's been clearly things
he's been avoiding like his own Terms of
Service the spending of money on London
real instead of you know the digital
freedom platform you know his his
unwillingness to move to platforms like
bit shoot to save all the fees the
likelihood of him being able to win a
lawsuit with $250,000 but he's in this
kind of careful balance tenuous
tightrope walk and it seems like the
house of cards may be about to fall down
but do you think there's anything he
could redeem here do you think there's
something some Redemption arc that makes
sense do you think there's an apology
that basically needs to be made do you
think the project needs to be scrapped
if you're Brian Rose where do you go
from here hmm
yeah that's that's a really good
question all the way through this I've
been sort of trying to yeah just to make
to keep in mind that there is a real
person on the end of this and not to get
dragged into because I think I said in
one of my last updates like the the
pattern that I see Brian doing and many
other people doing is what Venkatesh Rao
is called the Internet of beefs which is
that the
sentence structure of the Internet is
driving people more and more towards
combat and building armies and getting
what what
Rao called nights and MOOCs which is a
brilliant like it's a brilliant
brilliant article if anyone hasn't read
it and I've never seen a more obvious
transparent example of someone who
completely did dispenses with any of the
metaphors and just talks about creating
an army just goes all-out with the war
kind of talk it's it's it's kind of a
how to so how do you talk about this how
do you pay attention to it without
getting drawn into that same dynamic
yourself how do I get drawn into kind of
looking at it making films about it
without just feeding that dynamic and
one of them is this sort of and and it's
the morality tale like the psychological
dimensions and the morality tale of is
also just such a fascinating thing to
look at like what must it be like right
now to be in that space what must it be
like to be to have built what looks to
me into you like a kind of a trap for
yourself like it seems certainly on
Sunday and some of the comments of the
latest videos it does seem like the
audience is really starting to turn and
because it's one thing to put out a film
that people don't like it's another
thing to take lots of money off people
and then insult them for asking you
questions like that's a very different
dynamic like it's hard enough when
you're when when you put out a film that
your audience doesn't like it
god knows what it's like what you've
actually taken lots of money off them
for something and they're asking hey man
what happened to my money what happened
to this platform and so yeah the
psychological dimension of and someone
who's been open in the past about having
had addiction problems about having it's
like and I think a lot of people feel
that they know him like that's that's
part of the the journey with London real
is that people feel that they know who
Brian Rose is to some degree and I think
I said in my first film
my sense is there are two Brian roses
there's the there's the businessman
mentored by Dan penny
who is just this sort of ruthless
shafted grandmother to get ahead kind of
American and then there's also the guy
who was honest about his addiction
problems and has like those two things
exist at the same time I've had more
than one person who knows Brian Rose has
known Brian Rose for a while say that
that was absolutely accurate you can
almost picture him with like the the
better and the worse angels of his
nature on boat on either side and and
he's been more and more swayed towards
sort of the dan pena the multilevel
marketing the just kind of use your
gather as many emails as possible and
use it to to kind of get as much out of
your followers as you can and that's
been a trajectory and I don't see a way
out that does not involve some kind of
Mia culpa some kind of apology but human
psychology is very difficult like to
actually do that is extremely difficult
and I wonder how I don't know I and
that's part of this as well is like I
don't know when when and if something
like this comes crashing down what
people do and I think realizing that
that's yeah the balance of kind of
rights and responsibilities of do I have
a responsibility to call this out I
think so as I said in my first film I
think the whole double bind of freedom
of speech is that we have to use it and
it becomes a a self-correcting process
or we're probably going to lose it
because the big tech platforms are just
gonna say we're gonna decide who's
allowed to speak and who isn't so yeah
I've kind of wrestled with with this
from the beginning of like how can you
do this in a way that is honest is
authentic is not not seeing someone as
an enemy that needs to be
attacked but as someone who is like in
some ways there go all of us like some
of the some of the other things that
this brings up to me is like the weird
incentive structures of alternative
media sure like that there's lots of
these so basically this whole business
model of you have 2 million YouTube
subscribers there's a lot of there's a
lot of places like this now which have I
find in different ways to monetize
attention they have attention through
the people they've got on they get more
people to go on because of the all the
other people they've had go on so that's
there's a lot of those around there's a
lot of those around and the temptation
to like I mean rebel wisdom has
something like that as a business model
in that it's a it's a media channel
first and foremost but we also have to
pay the bills we have memberships we run
online courses so those so you can't
just say oh the business model is wrong
it's a much more nuanced conversation
than that it's like how can you know
when you're being authentic and when
you're you're not being authentic yeah
let me jump jump in here real quick cuz
I think I think it's fair to say that
okay maybe you know if I were in the
same shoes there go I whatever but I
think at the same time you have to be
aware that what he's done has when you
descend into the particular you can see
some definitely areas where he just went
wrong where he's talking about head
faking his audience you can't do that to
an audience when you're raising a
million dollars you just can't you can't
tell them hey I'm having to lie to you
about certain things you can't tell them
that you're gonna build a digital
freedom platform but then like weeks
later say oh by the way I've been using
free platforms all along and you should
have known that and then not explain why
you're not just using the most obvious
free speech platform that there is you
can't say that you're gonna stop
fundraising and then keep on fundraising
under the name of this value that we all
hold so dear but then really not stand
up to scrutiny when it's questioned do
you really stand up for that value at
all I think there are some very clear
areas where he's gone from okay
you can monetize an audience there are
ethical ways to monetize attention
nobody works for free but that's not
what's happening here that's not why
people are upset people are upset
because of the lying because of the
duplicity because of the hypocrisy the
gigantic gaping hypocrisy surrounding
this whole thing so while we can kind of
amuse that you know but for the grace of
God there go I all we want but at the
end of the day we can point to concrete
things that concretely has have been the
reason for his sort of downfall and the
reason that he's in the position that he
is I heard a friend of mine who was
talking to about this I think it really
sums up the way a lot of people are
feeling right now he goes man it's such
a shame what's been going on with London
real because the guy had so many great
guests on he goes I don't agree with
everything the guy said but he had some
really great guests on and he was
building a long-term reputation that was
gonna kind of last and build into
something sort of greater than what
London real currently is and that has
sort of been traded I mean this person
that had a pretty decent amount of
respect for this person it's close to
friend of mine no longer has that
respect he's like yeah I won't watch
another like what am I gonna watch the
guy who's having all the conspiracy
theorists on who's you know sort of
lying about the way he's handling this
money no he's not going to anymore and I
think a lot of people are wrestling with
this London real they had in their mind
like six weeks ago versus the London
real and the actions of Brian Rose that
they see before them today
nice little rant to end on sorry no it's
good it was good I think I think you're
right you're right I'm I'm trying to
hold all of those perspectives at the
same time I think you're right in in
that I'm wary of that dynamic of
unexamined judgment of other people
because that comes back and bite you in
the ass as well it sure does which is
why I think it's important to say and I
said it in my video yesterday but I
think that we should say here we have
both reached out to Brian Rose on
numerous occasions to give him the
chance to respond we have I've emailed
him four times David how many times do
you think you've emailed him six six
times so between us 10 times have we
reached out to Brian
in the effort of getting an examined
judgment in the effort of getting an
understood full 360 of the situation it
has not been us that is unwilling to
come to the table unfortunately it has
been Brian Rose for what he may have his
own reasons they might be good reasons
but it's been his decision to leave the
people who are criticizing him out of
the full picture and unfortunately if
that creates a skewed perspective at
some point that cannot be placed on our
shoulders yeah I agree I want you to be
my lawyer if it's ever needed now you
don't I I talk a big game but uh yeah
it's been a lot of fun kind of going
through this it's been interesting it
sort of been heartbreaking I've sort of
experienced the gamut of emotions
traversing this topic it's sort of been
the longest forum series that I've done
and it's been sort of the biggest fall
that I've seen I mean I don't know if
London rails reputation is as severely
wounded as I perceive it to be but it
seems it seems really bad and it's not
something that I relish and I try not to
get too bloodthirsty about these things
but um yeah it just is what it is I
guess yeah and it's all your fault
that's right I'm sure someone will come
on it'll be about the haters you know
the people that the criticizers the
malicious forces yeah it's the
controlled opposition that they're
paying is enough to don't say that even
as a joke hey it'd be great if I was
getting paid a bunch of money for this
I'm doing it because I love it
so so yeah I think that basically covers
it huh yeah that's really good Stephen
thank you and let's try to get this out
as soon as possible pleasure
rebel wisdom was set up to make sense of
the world at a deeper level than the
mainstream media it was built for these
times of crisis and change
which is why we want to do what we can
to meet the challenge of the times more
films and also for our rebel wisdom
members weekly sense-making calls with
our amazing interviewees and also we're
introducing the wisdom gym a place to
practice some of the skills that we've
talked about on the channel thanks for
watching and see you soon
[Music]